<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kevin W. Beam</title><link>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Kevin W. Beam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:32:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python References, Tools, and Articles</title><link>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/posts/python-references/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:32:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/posts/python-references/</guid><description>Some time ago I developed a strategy&amp;ndash;a brain hack, more accurately&amp;ndash;to deal with my unending cursed curiosity. Instead of the 47&amp;ndash;on average&amp;ndash;browser tabs accumulating and clogging my computer&amp;rsquo;s memory, I started accumulating a pile of links. This pile was meant to collect interesting new packages, articles, tutorials, videos, and the like, and of course I would read them all later. Of course. The first derivative of my link pile had long been positive, and a close inspection of the second derivative revealed that it too showed no sign of nearing negative territory.</description></item><item><title>Python References, Tools, and Articles</title><link>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/python/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:32:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/python/</guid><description>Official Python Python Home Python 3 Documentation The Python Tutorial The Python Language Reference The Python Standard Library Python Packaging Authority Python Packaging User Guide PyPI - The Python Package Index Conda &amp;amp; Mamba Conda Tools Conda Conda Build Miniconda Conda Lock Conda Pack Conda Store Mamba Conda Forge Anaconda.org Repository Python Version Management Pyenv Pyenv Virtualenv Plugin Linting &amp;amp; Formatting Flake8 Pylint Black Formatter Tool Type Annotations Mypy Typeshed Pyright Pytype Testing Pytest Coverage Hypothesis Responses Scientific Python SciPy Lectures SciPy NumPy SymPy Pandas Dask Xarray Zarr PyTables SciKit Image SciKit Learn Sci ML Visualization Matplotlib Seaborn Bokeh Kepler HoloViz Vega Lite Altair Plotnine Geospatial EPSG GDAL PySTAC CartoPy EarthPy Pangeo Iris ICESat-2 Sliderule ICESat-2 IcePyx Jupyter Notebooks Jupyter JupyterLab Papermill Jupytext Nbconvert ReviewNB Functional Programming O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Functional Python Programming Functional Programming Techniques in Python Funcy Toolz More Itertools Pymonad Returns Lenses Mary Rose Cook, A Practical Intro to Functional Programming Awesome Functional Python Documentation Diátaxis Framework What nobody tells you about documentation Write the Docs Documentation Read the Docs Hosting on RTD Documenting Python I Documenting Python II Awesome Awesome Python Awesome Functional Python Unreviewed Articles &amp;amp; Packages Functional Programming https://medium.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 10:32:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer at the National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC). NSIDC is part of the Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Sciences at the University of Colorado Boulder. I develop software for scientific data products, data analysis, and visualization. I work mainly in Python, JavaScript / TypeScript, and develop both on-prem and cloud (AWS) deployed systems.</description></item><item><title>Using pyenv to Simplify Python Development</title><link>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 10:32:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://kbeamnsidc.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><description>If you develop multiple Python projects each with their own version of Python, set of dependencies, and use both virtualenvs and conda, then pyenv is worth your time to investigate and learn. Check out the short demo:
To get started, install both pyenv and pyenv-virtualenv and integrate them into your shell setup. Both have good installation instructions and are easy to get up and running:
Pyenv Pyenv-virtualenv</description></item></channel></rss>